[["WORLD",
"INDIA",
"SCIENCE",
"TECH",
"Chemistry",
"GEOGRAPHY",
"HARRY POTTER"],
{"question": "The ratio of width of our National flag to its length is",
"options": ["2:3",
"3:5",
"2:4",
"3:4"],
"answer": "2:3",
"category": ["INDIA"]},
{"question": "Rabindranath Tagore's 'Jana Gana Mana' has been adopted as India's National Anthem. How many stanzas of the said song were adopted?",
"options": ["Only the first stanza",
"The whole song",
"Third and Fourth stanza",
"First and Second stanza"],
"answer": "Only the first stanza",
"category": ["INDIA"]},
{"question": "'Natya - Shastra' the main source of India's classical dances was written by",
"options": ["Bharat Muni",
"Nara Muni",
"Abhinav Gupt",
"Tandu Muni"],
"answer": "Bharat Muni",
"category": ["INDIA"]},
{"question": "'Dandia' is a popular dance of",
"options": ["Gujarat",
"Punjab",
"Tamil Nadu",
"Maharashtra"],
"answer": "Gujarat",
"category": ["INDIA"]},
{"question": "The words 'Satyameva Jayate' inscribed below the base plate of the emblem of India are taken from...",
"options": ["Mundak Upanishad",
"Rigveda",
"Satpath Brahmana",
"Ramayana"],
"answer": "Mundak Upanishad",
"category": ["INDIA"]},
{"question": "Where is located 'Indian Diamond Institute' in India?",
"options": ["Surat",
"Rajkot",
"Admedabad",
"Vadodara"],
"answer": "Surat",
"category": ["INDIA"]},
{"question": "Where is located 'Rubber Board' in India?",
"options": ["Kerala",
"Karnataka",
"Tamil Nadu",
"Andhra Pradesh"],
"answer": "Kerala",
"category": ["INDIA"]},
{"question": "Where is located ' Central Soil Salinity Research Institute' in India?",
"options": ["Haryana",
"Lucknow",
"Jaipur",
"Patna"],
"answer": "Haryana",
"category": ["INDIA"]},
{"question": "Where is located 'Central Rice Research Institute' in India?",
"options": ["Cuttack",
"Rourkela",
"Ranchi",
"Raigarh"],
"answer": "Cuttack",
"category": ["INDIA"]},
{"question": "Where is located 'Tobacco Board' in Andhra Pradesh?",
"options": ["Guntur",
"Kadapa",
"Ananthapur",
"Kakinada"],
"answer": "Guntur",
"category": ["INDIA"]},
{"question": "Where is located 'Central Institute for Cotton Research' in India?",
"options": ["Nagpur",
"Indore",
"Surat",
"Nashik"],
"answer": "Nagpur",
"category": ["INDIA"]},
{"question": "What category of people are most likely to suffer from progeria?",
"options": ["Children",
"Pregnant women",
"Asian men",
"People who own pet snakes"],
"answer": "Children",
"category": ["SCIENCE"]},
{"question": "Why do we see lightning before we hear it (in the form of thunder)?",
"options": ["Light travels faster than sound",
"Sonar myopia",
"Thunder is not related to lightning",
"Lightning disrupts human sensory organs"],
"answer": "Light travels faster than sound",
"category": ["SCIENCE"]},
{"question": "If you were to undergo a craniotomy, what part of your body would be opened up by the surgeon?",
"options": ["Skull",
"Abdomen",
"Chest",
"Leg"],
"answer": "Skull",
"category": ["SCIENCE"]},
{"question": "What do you call a flaw in a computer program?",
"options": ["bug",
"mugs",
"lug",
"dug"],
"answer": "bug",
"category": ["TECH"]},
{"question": "The element ruthenium was named after the Latin word for which bear-related country?",
"options": ["Russia",
"Peru",
"USA",
"Germany"],
"answer": "Russia",
"category": ["SCIENCE"]},
{"question": "Which of the following is not a part of human male reproductive system?",
"options": ["Cervix",
"Vas deferens",
"Testes",
"Scrotum"],
"answer": "Cervix",
"category": ["SCIENCE"]},
{"question": "Which is not a bone in the human body?",
"options": ["Meniscus",
"Tibia",
"Clavicle",
"Mandible"],
"answer": "Meniscus",
"category": ["SCIENCE"]},
{"question": "Which of the following words is defined as 'the ability of a liquid to resist flowing'?",
"options": ["Viscosity",
"Fluidity",
"Pourability",
"Freezability"],
"answer": "Viscosity",
"category": ["SCIENCE"]},
{"question": "Many modern timepieces use a certain crystal which, when shaped correctly, emits a frequency that can be accurately calculated. This creates a very accurate timepiece. Which crystal is used?",
"options": ["Quartz",
"Halite",
"Potassium dihydrogen phosphate",
"Diamond"],
"answer": "Quartz",
"category": ["Chemistry"]},
{"question": "Which of the following is the major difference between a compound and a molecule?",
"options": ["A compound always contains multiple elements",
"There is no difference!",
"A compound can only contain one element",
"A molecule does not involve chemical bonds"],
"answer": "A compound always contains multiple elements",
"category": ["SCIENCE"]},
{"question": "Joule is unit of...",
"options": ["Power",
"Impulse",
"Energy",
"Temperature"],
"answer": "Power",
"category": ["SCIENCE"]},
{"question": "Standing on a remote mountain peak, a surveyor can figure out where he is on his map by measuring the azimuth to two other points of reference that are more well known and the distance between them. What is this method commonly known as?",
"options": ["non-Euclidean geometry",
"Canonization",
"Disambiguation",
"Triangulation"],
"answer": "non-Euclidean geometry",
"category": ["SCIENCE"]},
{"question": "In which country, known for its sombreros and pi\u00f1atas, will you find the Copper Canyon?",
"options": ["Mexico",
"Cuba",
"Guatemala",
"Argentina"],
"answer": "Mexico",
"category": ["GEOGRAPHY"]},
{"question": "What was the traditional national sport of Spain?",
"options": ["Bull Fighting",
"Baseball",
"Cricket",
"Basketball"],
"answer": "Bull Fighting",
"category": ["GEOGRAPHY"]},
{"question": "How are earthquakes measured?",
"options": ["The Richter scale",
"The Fujita Scale",
"Speed",
"The TORRO scale"],
"answer": "The Richter scale",
"category": ["GEOGRAPHY"]},
{"question": "The 48-story Transamerica Pyramid is specially designed to withstand earthquakes. It is found in which Californian city known for its suspension bridge?",
"options": ["San Francisco",
"Sacramento",
"Hollywood",
"Los Angeles"],
"answer": "San Francisco",
"category": ["GEOGRAPHY"]},
{"question": "What is the highest mountain peak in California?",
"options": ["Mount Whitney",
"Mount Humphreys",
"Mount Pinchot",
"Guadalupe Peak"],
"answer": "Mount Whitney",
"category": ["GEOGRAPHY"]},
{"question": "Mauna Kea is the tallest mountain in the world, although this fact is not generally known. The majority of its height is hidden how?",
"options": ["Underwater",
"In the clouds",
"By buildings",
"Behind a lot of trees"],
"answer": "Underwater",
"category": ["GEOGRAPHY"]},
{"question": "Which of these cities of the world is not a European capital?",
"options": ["Cairo",
"Berlin",
"Prague",
"Kiev"],
"answer": "Cairo",
"category": ["GEOGRAPHY"]},
{"question": "What is the capital of Madhya Pradesh and the site of an ecological disaster in 1984?",
"options": ["Bhopal",
"Jammu",
"Punjab",
"Jaipur"],
"answer": "Bhopal",
"category": ["INDIA",
"GEOGRAPHY"]},
{"question": "What is the national animal of India ?",
"options": ["Royal Bengal Tiger",
"Goose",
"Peacock",
"Lion"],
"answer": "Royal Bengal Tiger",
"category": ["INDIA",
"GEOGRAPHY"]},
{"question": "Which city is known as Silicon Valley of India?",
"options": ["Bangalore",
"Pune",
"Hyderabad",
"Mumbai"],
"answer": "Bangalore",
"category": ["INDIA",
"GEOGRAPHY"]},
{"question": "As we move to the western part of India, we come to one of the most popular tourist spots known for its sun and sand. The place also has the first casino in India, which is this place?",
"options": ["Candolim",
"Chennai",
"Cochin",
"Mumbai"],
"answer": "Candolim",
"category": ["INDIA",
"GEOGRAPHY"]},
{"question": "This city is one of the union territories of India. It is highly influenced by French styles and is home to some of the best beaches in India like Promenade Beach. What is this place?",
"options": ["Pondicherry",
"Attur",
"Ernakulam",
"Mahabalipuram"],
"answer": "Pondicherry",
"category": ["INDIA",
"GEOGRAPHY"]},
{"question": "What is Hermione's cat's name?",
"options": ["Crookshanks",
"Errol",
"Scabbers",
"Hedwig"],
"answer": "Crookshanks",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "This spell causes a small beam of light to shine from the end of the caster's wand.",
"options": ["Lumos",
"Lumen",
"Glittos",
"Shiner"],
"answer": "Lumos",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "This spell causes things to rise in the air.",
"options": ["Wingardium Leviosa",
"Levitasium Willowsim",
"Rise Wing",
"Mudigarwin Sivolea"],
"answer": "Wingardium Leviosa",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "What does Dudley's gang call Dudley?",
"options": ["Big D",
"Dudler",
"Dudster",
"Spike"],
"answer": "Big D",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "In \"The Order of the Phoenix\" Harry visits 12 Grimmauld Place and encounters a portrait of Sirius' mother. What does she say to her son?",
"options": ["\"Blood traitor, shame of my flesh\"",
"\"Who are you, what's your name\"",
"\"Sirius would you please get me off this wall already\"",
"\"Why hello dear, how was your day\""],
"answer": "\"Blood traitor, shame of my flesh\"",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "Luna was a member of which group that rebelled against Professor Umbridge?",
"options": ["Dumbledore's Army",
"The Anti-Umbridge Act",
"The UnUmbridge group",
"Defence Alliance"],
"answer": "Dumbledore's Army",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "Who killed Dumbledore?",
"options": ["Severus Snape",
"Draco Malfoy",
"an unnamed Death Eater",
"Lord Voldemort"],
"answer": "Severus Snape",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "I am a female teacher. I am the Transfiguration teacher. I can turn into a tabby cat. I am often seen wearing tartan and I am very strict. I am the head of Gryffindor House, and the Deputy Headmistress. Who am I?",
"options": ["Minerva McGonagall",
"Pomona Sprout",
"Aurora Sinistra",
"Sybil Trelawny"],
"answer": "Minerva McGonagall",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "I am a Thestral. You can only see me if you have seen what?",
"options": ["Death",
"Pain",
"Hogwarts",
"Sadness"],
"answer": "Death",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "Who made the Sorcerer's Stone?",
"options": ["Nicolas Flamel",
"James Potter and Sirius Black",
"Voldemort",
"Professor Snape"],
"answer": "Nicolas Flamel",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "What did Mr Weasley enchant to make it fly?",
"options": ["A car",
"A broomstick",
"A chair",
"A house"],
"answer": "A car",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "When Harry goes into Snape's memory, what did Sirius and Harry's father call him?",
"options": ["Snivellus",
"GrivelyS",
"nuffles",
"Greasy"],
"answer": "Snivellus",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "What is Remus and Tonks' son's name?",
"options": ["Teddy",
"Ron",
"Harry",
"Peter"],
"answer": "Teddy",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "What is the killing curse?",
"options": ["Avada Kedavra",
"Sectumsempra",
"Ridikkulus",
"Accio"],
"answer": "Avada Kedavra",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "In the Harry Potter movie 'The Prisoner of Azkaban', Stan Shunpike struggles to get Harry's trunk on board the Knight Bus. What spell could he use, instead of trying to lift it himself?",
"options": ["Wingardium Leviosa",
"Lumos",
"Impedimenta",
"Ferula"],
"answer": "Wingardium Leviosa",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "\"We could all have been killed - or worse, expelled. Now, if you don't mind, I'm going to bed.\" Who said this?",
"options": ["Hermione Granger",
"Ron Weasley",
"Harry Potter",
"Lavender Brown"],
"answer": "Hermione Granger",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]},
{"question": "What did Snape tell Dumbledore about his love for Lily in his memories?",
"options": ["He would always love Lily.",
"He had forgotten her.",
"He did not love Lily anymore.",
"She would always be his friend."],
"answer": "He would always love Lily.",
"category": ["HARRY POTTER"]}]